<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Siglo Xix on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/siglo-xix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Siglo Xix on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 10:42:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/siglo-xix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stendhal a dit quelque part ceci, ou à peu près: J’écris pour une dizaine d’âmes que je ne verrai peut-être jamais, mais que j’adore, sans les avoir vues.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/06/20/stendhal-a-dit-quelque-part-ceci-ou-%C3%A0-peu-pr%C3%A8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 10:42:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/06/20/stendhal-a-dit-quelque-part-ceci-ou-%C3%A0-peu-pr%C3%A8s/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Society everywhere is in conspiracy against the manhood of every one of its members. Society is a joint-stock company, in which the members agree, for the better securing of his bread to each shareholder, to surrender the liberty and culture of the eater. The virtue in most request is conformity. Self-reliance is its aversion. It loves not realities and creators, but names and customs.
Whoso would be a man must be a nonconformist. He who would gather immortal palms must not be hindered by the name of goodness, but must explore if it be goodness. Nothing is at last sacred but the integrity of your own mind. Absolve you to yourself, and you shall have the suffrage of the world.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/05/28/society-everywhere-is-in-conspiracy-against-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 08:38:34 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/05/28/society-everywhere-is-in-conspiracy-against-the/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the woods, we return to reason and faith. There I feel that nothing can befall me in life,—no disgrace, no calamity, ( leaving me my eyes,) which nature cannot repair. Standing on the bare ground,—my head bathed by the blithe air, and uplifted into infinite space,—all mean egotism vanishes. I become a transparent eye-ball; I am nothing; I see all; the currents of the Universal Being circulate through me; I am part or particle of God.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/05/20/in-the-woods-we-return-to-reason-and-faith-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 13:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/05/20/in-the-woods-we-return-to-reason-and-faith-there/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Un buen militar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/12/28/un-buen-militar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 17:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/12/28/un-buen-militar/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
