<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arte on Nostalgia del Reino</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/tags/arte/</link><description>Recent content in Arte on Nostalgia del Reino</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nostalgiadelreino.net/tags/arte/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Number 11</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2016/12/10/Number-11/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2016/12/10/Number-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anoche, en la exposición sobre el &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstract_expressionism" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Expresionismo Abstracto&lt;/a>, en la &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.royalacademy.org.uk/exhibition/abstract-expressionism" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Royal Academy&lt;/a>, no fue, como habría esperado, alguno de los Rothkos lo que más me impresionó, sino el &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Number_11,_1952_%28painting%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>&lt;em>Number 11&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, o &lt;em>Blue Poles&lt;/em>, de &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jackson_Pollock" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Jackson Pollock&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>![Number 11]({{ site.url }}/images/number_11.jpg)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quizás porque así percibo ahora mi vida. El más absoluto caos, sin ningún mensaje aparente, ni un camino claro. Una ininteligible sucesión de hechos (desgracias y bendiciones, pero más desgracias que bendiciones) demasiado grandes, demasiado abrumadores. La vida, al final, no parece ni una habitación ni un camino, ni escaleras ni serpientes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sin embargo, en 1950, cuando Time citó una crítica donde se describía la obra de Pollock como caótico, este respondió contundentemente con un telegrama: &lt;em>“No chaos, damn it.”&lt;/em>. Todo en su obra, es intencional. Hay un patrón, hay un orden que él veía, y que yo no.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>¿Es también así nuestra existencia?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jilgueros</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2014/06/28/jilgueros/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 17:58:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2014/06/28/jilgueros/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Ford</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2013/04/04/ford/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2013/04/04/ford/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Miré los muros de la patria mía</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2012/12/21/mir%C3%A9-los-muros-de-la-patria-m%C3%ADa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2012/12/21/mir%C3%A9-los-muros-de-la-patria-m%C3%ADa/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>hace unos días en la haya en</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2012/09/20/hace-unos-d%C3%ADas-en-la-haya-en/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 19:37:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2012/09/20/hace-unos-d%C3%ADas-en-la-haya-en/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Hace unos días, en La Haya, en el &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Gemeentemuseum&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> (que significa “Museo Municipal”, aunque no me había enterado hasta ahora), descubriendo a un &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Mondrian&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> desconocido para mí, muy diferente de las maravillosas geometrías de colores.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contra la Literatura</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2012/06/26/contra-la-literatura/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 13:05:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2012/06/26/contra-la-literatura/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Dos años con Dylan</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2010/10/19/dos-a%C3%B1os-con-dylan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 12:05:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2010/10/19/dos-a%C3%B1os-con-dylan/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>El Gran Dictador</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2009/11/25/el-gran-dictador/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 04:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2009/11/25/el-gran-dictador/</guid><description>&lt;p>Uno de los momentos más bellos y en que se han dicho más verdades de la historia del cine, y de toda la historia del siglo XX&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->I’m sorry, but I don’t want to be an Emperor - that’s not my business. I don’t want to rule or conquer anyone. I should like to help everyone, if possible – Jew, gentile, black man, white. We all want to help one another; human beings are like that. We want to live by each other’s happiness, not by each other’s misery. We don’t want to hate and despise one another. In this world there’s room for everyone and the good earth is rich and can provide for everyone.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->The way of life can be free and beautiful.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->But we have lost the way.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Greed has poisoned men’s souls, has barricaded the world with hate, has goose-stepped us into misery and bloodshed. We have developed speed but we have shut ourselves in. Machinery that gives abundance has left us in want. Our knowledge has made us cynical, our cleverness hard and unkind. We think too much and feel too little. More than machinery, we need humanity. More than cleverness, we need kindness and gentleness. Without these qualities, life will be violent and all will be lost.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->The aeroplane and the radio have brought us closer together. The very nature of these inventions cries out for the goodness in men, cries out for universal brotherhood for the unity of us all. Even now my voice is reaching millions throughout the world, millions of despairing men, women, and little children, victims of a system that makes men torture and imprison innocent people.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->To those who can hear me I say, “Do not despair.” The misery that is now upon us is but the passing of greed, the bitterness of men who fear the way of human progress. The hate of men will pass and dictators die; and the power they took from the people will return to the people and so long as men die, liberty will never perish.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Soldiers: Don’t give yourselves to brutes, men who despise you, enslave you, who regiment your lives, tell you what to do, what to think and what to feel; who drill you, diet you, treat you like cattle, use you as cannon fodder. Don’t give yourselves to these unnatural men, machine men, with machine minds and machine hearts! You are not machines! You are not cattle! You are men! You have the love of humanity in your hearts. You don’t hate; only the unloved hate, the unloved and the unnatural.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Soldiers: Don’t fight for slavery! Fight for liberty! In the seventeenth chapter of Saint Luke it is written, “the kingdom of God is within man” – not one man, nor a group of men, but in all men, in you, you the people have the power, the power to create machines, the power to create happiness. You the people have the power to make this life free and beautiful, to make this life a wonderful adventure.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Then, in the name of democracy, let us use that power! Let us all unite!! Let us fight for a new world, a decent world that will give men a chance to work, that will give you the future and old age a security. By the promise of these things, brutes have risen to power, but they lie! They do not fulfill their promise; they never will. Dictators free themselves, but they enslave the people!! Now, let us fight to fulfill that promise!! Let us fight to free the world, to do away with national barriers, to do away with greed, with hate and intolerance. Let us fight for a world of reason, a world where science and progress will lead to all men’s happiness.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Soldiers: In the name of democracy, let us all unite!!!&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Hannah, can you hear me? Wherever you are, look up, Hannah. The clouds are lifting. The sun is breaking through. We are coming out of the darkness into the light. We are coming into a new world, a kindlier world, where men will rise above their hate, their greed and brutality.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Look up, Hannah. The soul of man has been given wings, and at last he is beginning to fly. He is flying into the rainbow – into the light of hope, into the future, the glorious future that belongs to you, to me, and to all of us. Look up, Hannah. Look up.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sobre Capra</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2009/02/11/sobre-capra/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2009 05:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2009/02/11/sobre-capra/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Revolutionary Road</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2009/01/28/revolutionary-road/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 10:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2009/01/28/revolutionary-road/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Interludio: Cine y Verdad</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2009/01/05/interludio-cine-y-verdad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2009/01/05/interludio-cine-y-verdad/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>To see a world in a grain of sand</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2008/10/16/to-see-a-world-in-a-grain-of-sand/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2008 11:31:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2008/10/16/to-see-a-world-in-a-grain-of-sand/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Pasión</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2008/09/24/pasi%C3%B3n/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 05:33:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2008/09/24/pasi%C3%B3n/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bach es diferente. Bach es la paz, la serenidad, la sensación de que hay en el Universo un orden superior, una finalidad, que no estamos solos. Bach es calidez, compasión, amor. Es esa sensación de que, al final, todo saldrá bien.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Nada de la violencia de Beethoven (&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->“Así golpea el Destino a la puerta”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->, dijo sobre su Quinta Sinfonía) tiene sitio aquí. Es la victoria del Orden sobre el Caos, la perfección.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Escuchando la Pasión Según San Mateo, ¿cómo no creer en Dios, aunque sea por unos instantes? En algún dios. En Yahvé, o Apolo, o el dios panteísta de Einstein (&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->creo en el Dios de Spinoza&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->, decía), o en nosotros mismos como criaturas divinas, poseedoras de esos tesoros que son la vida, la consciencia.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Escucho a Bach, y, mientras, ya no tengo miedo.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Soy una estrella que viaja contigo, brillando desde la oscuridad&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->, se decía en la liturgia de Mithra, el Sol Invicto. Bach es esa luz.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dorothea Lange</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2008/09/16/dorothea-lange/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 07:44:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2008/09/16/dorothea-lange/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Las uvas de la ira</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2008/09/15/las-uvas-de-la-ira/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 21:04:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2008/09/15/las-uvas-de-la-ira/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Infernáculo. Laberinto.</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2007/08/21/infern%C3%A1culo-laberinto/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2007 08:53:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2007/08/21/infern%C3%A1culo-laberinto/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Bacon y las Eumenides</title><link>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2007/06/27/bacon-y-las-eumenides/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 18:56:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://nostalgiadelreino.net/2007/06/27/bacon-y-las-eumenides/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item></channel></rss>